<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<featuresystem>
	<function class="org.maltparser.core.syntaxgraph.feature.DGraphAddressFunction" hasSubFunctions="true">
		<desc><![CDATA[ The dependency graph address functions take a graph node as argument and navigates from this graph node to another 
		graph node (if possible). There are seven dependency graph address functions: ]]></desc>
		<subfunctions>
			<subfunction name="head">Returns the head of the graph node if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
			<subfunction name="ldep">Returns the leftmost (left) dependent of the graph node if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
			<subfunction name="rdep">Returns the rightmost (right) dependent of the graph node if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
			<subfunction name="rdep2"></subfunction>
			<subfunction name="lsib">Returns the next left (same-side) sibling of the graph node if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
			<subfunction name="rsib">Returns the next right (same-side) sibling of the graph node if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
			<subfunction name="pred">Returns the predecessor of the graph node in the linear order of the input string if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
			<subfunction name="succ">Returns the successor of the graph node in the linear order of the input string if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
			<subfunction name="anc">Returns the ancestor of the graph node if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
			<subfunction name="panc">Returns the proper ancestor of the graph node if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
			<subfunction name="ldesc">Returns the leftmost descendant of the graph node if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
			<subfunction name="pldesc">Returns the proper leftmost descendant of the graph node if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
			<subfunction name="rdesc">Returns the rightmost descendant of the graph node if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
			<subfunction name="prdesc">Returns the proper rightmost descendant of the graph node if defined; otherwise, a null-value.</subfunction>
		</subfunctions>
	</function>
	<function class="org.maltparser.parser.algorithm.nivre.NivreFactory" hasSubFunctions="true" hasFactory="true">
		<subfunctions>
			<subfunction name="Stack"></subfunction>
			<subfunction name="Input"></subfunction>
		</subfunctions>
	</function>
	<function class="org.maltparser.parser.algorithm.planar.PlanarFactory" hasSubFunctions="true" hasFactory="true">
		<subfunctions>
			<subfunction name="Stack"></subfunction>
			<subfunction name="Input"></subfunction>
		</subfunctions>
	</function>
	<function class="org.maltparser.parser.algorithm.twoplanar.TwoPlanarFactory" hasSubFunctions="true" hasFactory="true">
		<subfunctions>
			<subfunction name="ActiveStack"></subfunction>
			<subfunction name="InactiveStack"></subfunction>
			<subfunction name="Input"></subfunction>
		</subfunctions>
	</function>
	<function class="org.maltparser.parser.algorithm.stack.StackFactory" hasSubFunctions="true" hasFactory="true">
		<subfunctions>
			<subfunction name="Stack"></subfunction>
			<subfunction name="Input"></subfunction>
			<subfunction name="Lookahead"></subfunction>
		</subfunctions>
	</function>
	<function class="org.maltparser.parser.algorithm.covington.CovingtonFactory" hasSubFunctions="true" hasFactory="true">
		<subfunctions>
			<subfunction name="Left"></subfunction>
			<subfunction name="Right"></subfunction>
			<subfunction name="LeftContext"></subfunction>
			<subfunction name="RightContext"></subfunction>
		</subfunctions>
	</function>	
	<function name="InputColumn" class="org.maltparser.core.syntaxgraph.feature.InputColumnFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ The column name must correspond to an input column in the data format and the address function 
		must return a token node in the input string. (If the address function is undefined, a null-value is returned.) ]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="OutputColumn" class="org.maltparser.core.syntaxgraph.feature.OutputColumnFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ The column name must correspond to an output column in the data format and the address function 
		must return a graph node in the dependency graph. (If the address function is undefined, a null-value is returned.) ]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="InputTable" class="org.maltparser.core.syntaxgraph.feature.InputTableFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ This is a internal feature for MaltParser to address internal symbol table. (If the address function is undefined, a null-value is returned.) ]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="OutputTable" class="org.maltparser.core.syntaxgraph.feature.OutputTableFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ This is a internal feature for MaltParser to address internal symbol table. (If the address function is undefined, a null-value is returned.) ]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="InputArc" class="org.maltparser.core.syntaxgraph.feature.InputArcFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ Takes three arguments, a column name and two address functions, and returns LEFT, RIGHT or NULL depending on whether 
		the column value defines a left-pointing, right-pointing or no arc between the two nodes identified by the address functions. The column name 
		must correspond to an <b>input</b> column of integer type in the data format and the address functions must return token nodes in 
		the input string. (If one of the address functions is undefined, a null-value is returned.) This feature function can be used to define 
		features over the dependency graph predicted by another parser and given as input to MaltParser.]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="InputArcDir" class="org.maltparser.core.syntaxgraph.feature.InputArcDirFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ Takes two arguments, a column name and an address function, and returns LEFT, RIGHT or ROOT depending on whether the column 
		value defines the head of the node identified by the address function to be situated on the left or on the right or to be the artificial root 
		node. The column name must correspond to an <b>input</b> column of integer type in the data format and the address function must return 
		a token node in the input string. (If the address function is undefined, a null-value is returned.) This feature function can be used to define 
		features over the dependency graph predicted by another parser and given as input to MaltParser.]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="Exists" class="org.maltparser.core.syntaxgraph.feature.ExistsFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ Takes an address function as argument and returns TRUE if the address function returns an existing 
		node (and FALSE otherwise).]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="Distance" class="org.maltparser.core.syntaxgraph.feature.DistanceFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ Takes three arguments, two address functions and a normalization string, and returns the string distance (number of 
		intervening words) between the words identified by the address functions. The normalization string is a list of integers (separated by "|") 
		specifying the intervals used to discretize the distance metric. The list must start with 0 and be sorted in ascending order. The value 
		returned is (a category corresponding to) the greatest integer in the normalization string that is smaller than or equal to the exact distance.  ]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="NumOf" class="org.maltparser.core.syntaxgraph.feature.NumOfFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ Takes three arguments, an address function, a relation name, and a normalization string, and returns the 
		number of nodes having the specified relation to the node identified by the address function. Valid relation names are <b>ldep</b>, 
		<b>rdep</b> and <b>dep</b> (for left dependent, right dependent and dependent, respectively). The normalization string is a list 
		of integers (separated by "|") specifying the intervals used to discretize the metric. The list must start with 0 and be sorted in 
		ascending order. The value returned is (a category corresponding to) the greatest integer in the normalization string that is smaller 
		than or equal to the exact number.   ]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="Split" class="org.maltparser.core.feature.map.SplitFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ Splits the feature value into a set of feature values. In addition to 
		a feature specification it takes a delimiter (regular expression) as an argument.  ]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="Suffix" class="org.maltparser.core.feature.map.SuffixFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ Extract the suffix of a feature value with a suffix length n. By convention, if n = 0, the entire 
		feature value is included; otherwise only the n last characters are included in the feature value.   ]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="Prefix" class="org.maltparser.core.feature.map.PrefixFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ Extract the prefix of a feature value with a prefix length n. By convention, if n = 0, the entire 
		feature value is included; otherwise only the n first characters are included in the feature value.   ]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="Merge" class="org.maltparser.core.feature.map.MergeFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ Merge two feature value into one feature value.  ]]></desc>
	</function>
	<function name="Merge3" class="org.maltparser.core.feature.map.Merge3Feature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ Merge three feature value into one feature value.  ]]></desc>
	</function>
		<function name="OutputArc" class="org.maltparser.core.syntaxgraph.feature.OutputArcFeature" hasSubFunctions="false">
		<desc><![CDATA[ Takes three arguments, a column name and two address functions, and returns LEFT, RIGHT or NULL depending on whether 
		the column value defines a left-pointing, right-pointing or no arc between the two nodes identified by the address functions. The column name 
		must correspond to an <b>output</b> column of integer type in the data format and the address functions must return token nodes in 
		the input string. (If one of the address functions is undefined, a null-value is returned.) IMPORTANT NOTE: Currently the column name is
		ignored, it only works for arcs described by the HEAD output column. ]]></desc>
	</function>
</featuresystem>

